Freddie Groom Canberra, Australia github.com/fredgroom - fredgroom@gmail.com remote – on-site in Canberra – hybrid roles outside Canberra

I am a user-focused developer with over 4 years of professional experience in building responsive, data-driven web applications using React and TypeScript. I build responsive data-driven web interfaces with reusable components and am comfortable refactoring existing projects or building from the ground up. I meet project deadlines when requirements need to be extended, both independently and within multidisciplinary teams.

I have a keen appreciation for UX/UI design, demonstrated through my initiative in teaching colleagues Figma to improve software design processes. My diverse background, including coaching and studying osteopathy, enhances my problem-solving and interpersonal skills, proving invaluable for delivering features, managing and mentoring colleagues and interacting with clients. In my free time, I explore new technologies and build projects for charity. I relocated from London to Canberra in 2023 and focussed the time applying for permanent residency expanding my back-end skill set, to deliver full-stack apps, through online courses and I started a part-time bachelor's degree to broaden my understanding of computer science. References are available on request.

Skills - Typescript - Javascript - NextJS - React - React Native - Redux - Storybook - Styled-components - Node.js - Express - CSS - HTML5 - Git - HTML - MongoDB - Mongoose - SQL - Postgresql - AWS

Consulting, Volunteering and ongoing projects, January 2023 - Present **Sounds Super Podcasts**, <u>soundssuper.co</u>,

Designed, built, deployed and now maintain Sounds Super's website. I used React, TypeScript, and TailwindCss, AWS S3 for hosting and managed DNS records with route 53.

Ideals Charity, <u>ideals.freddiegroom.com.</u> Redesigned and built the website for Ideals Disaster Relief Charity. I used React, NextJS, TypeScript and Styled-Components. I am implementing Strapi as a Headless CMS to allow content management. It is hosted with AWS S3 and DNS records are managed with route 53.

Homebase, *tbd*, Building a mobile app for a health and fitness startup. I am using React-Native, TypeScript, Styled-Components, Django and Postres.

Productivity Dashboard, *tbd*, I am building a productivity dashboard with React, TypeScript, Material-UI, Dexie, IndexedDB, Node, Express, MongoOse, MongoDB and Passport.

Employment

Associate Developer, Decision Technology Ltd, *Mar* 2019 — *Jan* 2023, London UK Built variants of client products to capture consumer insights for forecasting and product development. Contributed throughout the software development lifecycle on legacy and greenfield projects.

- Independently delivered numerous experiments, built with React, TypeScript, Redux, and Storybook.
- Routinely worked extra hours for client deadlines when requirements were extended.
- Championed agile methodologies, improving the existing software design process for optimised workflow and reduced project duration, leading company-wide and individual training on Figma.
- Mentored junior developers helping cultivate a friendly and supportive team environment
- Managed Python automation scripts on Amazon EC2.
- Provided technical support as needed.

Mentor, Bright Network Coding Bootcamp, Mar 2021 - May 2021, London UK

- Supported graduates during a remote software engineering boot camp.
- Coached mentees through technical questions and when delivering projects.
- Received overwhelmingly positive feedback from course management and attendees.

Senior Crossfit Coach, Crossfit Vauxhall London, Mar 2012 - Mar 2019, London UK

- Analysed client progress to optimise program efficiency from data insights.
- Developed automated training programs with Excel.
- Instructed large groups and individuals in safe and efficient exercise.
- Customised exercises for individual requirements, injuries and access to equipment.
- Completed numerous courses for continued professional development

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, University of London, 2023 - present
A part-time online course through Coursera to help broaden my knowledge of Computer
Science.

Full Stack Development Bootcamp, Red Academy, *Apr 2018 — Oct 2018,* London UK A full-time coding boot camp with two industry placements while working full-time. Delivered MVPs for two start-ups, Mapify - WordPress and PHP, and Herd - React-Native and Postgres. I was taught HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Gulp, SASS, PHP, WordPress, git and GitHub, React, Redux, Node.JS, Express, Postgresql and MongoDB, Meteor, React Native, Cloud Deployment and TDD.

British School of Osteopathy, 2012 — 2016, London UK

- Developed enhanced diagnostic, problem-solving, and communication skills.
- Learned human anatomy and physiology

Volunteering

I have volunteered extensively with children with significant learning disabilities, coaching young people and now enjoy building websites for charities.